QIWEI ZHANG

g.zhang0320201@arts.ac.uk · +44 07419736862 · https://www.giweizhang.com

PROFILE: Creative Computing Institute in UAL student with an interdisciplinary focus on the intersection of sensory experience design, cognitive science, and interactive computing, and created a series of projects called "FLOW" exploring brainwave sensory interactions. As a former co-founder of immersive experience startups, I have experimented with a lot of sensors and tangible interactions. Moreover, several internships equip me exceptionally well to conduct future research that will focus on mixed reality and augmented sensory experience.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ARTS LONDON, UK

Sep 2021 - Present

MSc Creative Computing

- Related thesis: Sensory experience of multimodel interactive design
- Related courses: Physical computing, machine learning, user-centred interactive experience design

SHANGHAI INSTITUTE OF VISUAL ARTS, CHINA

Sep 2016 - Jun 2020

BA Digital Media Art

- Honors 2:1; GPA 3.35/4; Top 5 Related courses: creative digital media, UX, interactive design, art installation
- Chairman of the Career Development Alliance, a startup in immersive sensory experience
- Thesis: exploring the visualization and emotional control of brainwaves in interactive art
- Awards: 1/26 students with Outstanding Graduate, Outstanding Thesis and Outstanding Project

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Social machine learning program research assistant - UAL

Jul 2022 - Present

- Built a local server for machine learning, and established a database of student text and project information
- Supported students to set up prompts in a no-code environment and rendered their own works through Slack

Summer school 'Community Smart Design' student – Tongji University

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

Transformed a factory in Shanghai into an art galary for AI exhibition, using 'Touchdesigner' data visualization

"Architectural intelligence workshop student – DigitalFuture Forum

Jun 2021 - Jul 2021

- Assisted with completing the generative machine learning workflow
- Achieved the tech from 2D Style Transfer, 3D Generative Models to architecture

"A Brief History of Computing Art" exhibition technician - UCCA

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

- Researched and developed a radar-positioning interactive art installation, through 'Touchdesigner' software
- The programme operated automously without any human intervention during its four-month international exhibition

WORK EXPERIENCE

HUAWEI Technologies Co., Ltd

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- User Research Intern
- Created user insight reports through in-depth interviews and qualitative analyses with 30 target users
- In charge of the metaverse program competitive product analysis reports and product blueprints
- Finalised user-generated templates with the social metaverse team in the AR campus to improve content quality

Zhiwei Robot Co., Ltd (DFRobot)

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021

CEO Assistance Intern

- Responsible for creating a customised recommendation strategy to improve the repurchase rate
- Collaborated with designers and strategists on a product manager training system, increasing efficiency by 30%
- Managed the CEO's calendar, identified and resolved contract risk, and followed up on 4 projects

White Beard Culture Communication Co., Ltd

Apr 2018 - Aug 2019

Co-founder

- Created an immersive escape room, attracting >10,000 offline players per year
- Designed and programmed three original immersive escape game experiences
- Led a team in building and operating both online and offline, including promotion on public media platforms
- Achieved better usex sr experience on all customer platforms, and ranked top 2 in Shanghai Songjiang district

EXHIBITION & AWARDS

•	Beyond Nature Bio-design Exhibition in London	Dec 2021
•	Project 'Calm Flow' selected in Art & Design Education FutureLab	Nov 2020
•	Individual Award of the 5th Think Youth-Shanghai New Media International Competition	Aug 2020
•	Excellent Graduation Project and was collected by the School	Jun 2020
•	Third Prize of Creative New Media in the First China Creativity Festival of University	Jun 2020
•	The 6th Internet+ University Student Innovation and Entrepreneurship Excellent Project	Mar 2019

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: Adobe Kit; Python; C/C++ (Arduino); Touchdesigner; HTML/JavaScript; C4D; Unity; Blender
- Languages: English (Fluent); Mandarin (Native)